<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>rooting android &#8211; AhteVirusHub</title>
	<atom:link href="https://github.com/AhteVirus/AhteVirusHub/tag/rooting-android/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://github.com/AhteVirus/AhteVirusHub</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 04:51:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Methods of rooting an Android Device</title>
		<link>https://github.com/AhteVirus/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/02/methods-of-rooting-an-android-device/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/AhteVirus/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/02/methods-of-rooting-an-android-device/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ahtesham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 04:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android access]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to root android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[root android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rooting android]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ahtevirus.tech/?p=56</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There isn&#8217;t only one method available to root all android devices. Instead, every device has different ways to get rooted. However, Several methods are common, from which anyone can help root your device. Some of the methods to root your device without using a PC are as follows: Magisk Root With the Magisk root application,&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://github.com/AhteVirus/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/02/methods-of-rooting-an-android-device/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Methods of rooting an Android Device</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>There isn&#8217;t only one method available to <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#">root</a> all android devices. Instead, every device has different ways to get rooted. However, Several methods are common, from which anyone can help root your device.</p>



<p>Some of the methods to root your device without using a PC are as follows:</p>



<ul>
<li><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ffa500;">Magisk Root</span></li>
</ul>



<p>With the <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Magisk root</a> application, many android devices can get root access. It is an open-source project. As we know that after rooting our device, we don&#8217;t get any OTA update and as the process of rooting your device is not easy, you become frustrated while rooting and unrooting your device. Magisk brings a solution for your frustration, as it is a systemless rooting system, as you can grant root access without touching your device&#8217;s core code.</p>



<ul>
<li><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ffa500;">Framaroot</span></li>
</ul>



<p><a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Framaroot</a> is another application allowing you to root your android device without using a PC. However, it&#8217;s easy to root a device using this application, but a deficient number of devices are supported on their platform. Still, you can try to find with your device&#8217;s name and model number, whether it is supported on their platform or not from <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#">here</a>.</p>



<ul>
<li><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ffa500;">KingRoot</span></li>
</ul>



<p><a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">KingRoot</a> is the application allowing one tap root to its users. It supports several devices to give root access easily on their platform. Indeed, it&#8217;s the first application I used to root my device and learn more about them. However, not every device is supported on their platform but can try that application as it never harms your device.</p>



<ul>
<li><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ffa500;">CF-Auto-Root</span></li>
</ul>



<p><a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CF-Auto-Root</a> is an application created by XDA developers. For beginners who have no or little knowledge about rooting android devices can use this application with closed eyes. However, this application is only used for Samsung and Nexus stock firmware. If you use this application, stay calm as there is no harm because it only installs SuperSU and enables root access.</p>



<ul>
<li><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ffa500;">Virtual Xposed Framework</span></li>
</ul>



<p>Unlike other applications, <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Virtual Xposed</a> never provides full root access in your device, instead, you can install an application that needs root access on their platform and use it. It&#8217;s a free way of gaining root access and consists of a very easy to use framework. The application itself acts as a gateway to root. However, not everything is possible by using this application. But it can give a good experience of a rooted device.</p>



<ul>
<li><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ffa500;">Android x86 Operating System</span></li>
</ul>



<p>Another way of enjoying root access is by installing android x86 OS on your PC. These you can dual boot your PC with such OS and use those for experimental purposes. These Android OS&#8217;s come with pre-installed root access to enable a switch to gain root access. It&#8217;s fun using such operating systems, as you can enjoy a full android framework on PC with total control. Some examples of such OS&#8217;s are <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bliss OS</a>, <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Phoenix OS</a>, <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Remix OS</a>, and several other <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">x86 OS</a>.</p>



<p>Now it depends on which method you will choose to root your device. However, always stay sure before rooting your device as the method you are using could work or not. Else use virtual Xposed and x86 OS type frameworks to experience root access.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/AhteVirus/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/02/methods-of-rooting-an-android-device/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Android Rooting</title>
		<link>https://github.com/AhteVirus/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/01/android-rooting/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/AhteVirus/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/01/android-rooting/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ahtesham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 20:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android access]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rooting android]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ahtevirus.tech/?p=42</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What is Rooting Android? No, it&#8217;s not the root of any tree, but the root of android. The rooting process allows the users of the mobile, tablet, or any platform that runs on the Android operating system to gain overall privileged control over the android subsystem. As android uses Linux Kernel, when we root our&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://github.com/AhteVirus/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/01/android-rooting/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Android Rooting</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="has-text-color" style="color:#ffa500">What is Rooting Android?</h2>



<p>No, it&#8217;s not the root of any tree, but the root of android. The rooting process allows the users of the mobile, tablet, or any platform that runs on the Android operating system to gain overall privileged control over the android subsystem. As android uses Linux Kernel, when we root our android, it provides equal access to administrative permissions as on Linux-based operating systems like Unix, macOS, FreeBSD, etc.</p>



<h2 class="has-text-color" style="color:#ffa500">Are there any benefits of rooting android?</h2>



<p>Rooting your android platform has several benefits. Some of the services are as follows:</p>



<ul><li>Take control</li></ul>



<p>It provides an opportunity to back control of your device. Many or most of the android platforms restrict their users to customize the software infrastructures, not with bad intention but to prevent accidental damage of its infrastructure.</p>



<ul><li>Free up space by removing bloatware</li></ul>



<p>In new smartphones, the manufacturers preinstall some bloatware as the developers get paid to preinstall those applications, and it usually gets impossible to remove such apps. However, with full control, we can easily remove those applications which are not useful for us by merely rooting the device.</p>



<ul><li>Custom Roms</li></ul>



<p>In a rooted device, you also can install custom ROMs and enjoy several different types of operating systems. You can install other operating systems and alternative software kernels. This feature can help you enjoy new features without purchasing new devices. Some use this feature to update new android versions in tools that get no updates.</p>



<h2 class="has-text-color" style="color:#ffa500">Not only advantages, but it also consists of several disadvantages.</h2>



<p>Everything in the world has disadvantages with advantages. Similarly, rooting your device also consists of several disadvantages. Some of them as follows:</p>



<ul><li>Voids the warranty</li></ul>



<p>If you root your device, the warranty of such devices gets void by the manufacturer. As you gain the root access, the moment your warranty gets void. Afterward, if something happens to your software or hardware, your manufacturer will never fix such problems. However, rooting an android device isn&#8217;t illegal in any country.</p>



<ul><li>Chances of brick</li></ul>



<p>While rooting your device, there remain precarious chances that your device gets bricked. However, it is a rare possibility, and such problems only occur when you don&#8217;t root your device correctly. Every device has different ways and variables to get rooted, and if you don&#8217;t have a great idea about that, it would be better to ask someone else to make that possible for you. However, bricked devices can be fixed by flashing firmware.</p>



<ul><li>Makes devices vulnerable</li></ul>



<p>No other devices are as vulnerable as rooted devices. After rooting your device, you might get access to several features. Still, you have to be very selective while downloading and using any applications, as it stops scanning for malicious applications and allows everything to run on your device.</p>



<ul><li>Losing access to secure applications</li></ul>



<p>Rooting might make you lose several high-security applications like payment applications. Several apps with high-security checks whether your device is rooted or not after that, it starts functioning. However, losing access to some essential applications can cause several difficulties.</p>



<p>If you think rooting your device is worthy, then first get a piece of useful knowledge about rooting devices, and then after thinking intelligently, take steps ahead to root your android device.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/AhteVirus/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/01/android-rooting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
