<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>how to root android &#8211; AhteVirusHub</title>
	<atom:link href="https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/tag/how-to-root-android/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub</link>
	<description>Connecting You to Technology</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 04:51:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cropped-ahtevirus_lab1-1-150x150.png</url>
	<title>how to root android &#8211; AhteVirusHub</title>
	<link>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Methods of rooting an Android Device</title>
		<link>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/02/methods-of-rooting-an-android-device/</link>
					<comments>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/02/methods-of-rooting-an-android-device/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ahtesham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 04:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android access]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to root android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[root android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rooting android]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ahtevirus.tech/?p=56</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There isn&#8217;t only one method available to root all android devices. Instead, every device has different ways to get rooted. However, Several methods are common, from which anyone can help root your device. Some of the methods to root your device without using a PC are as follows: Magisk Root With the Magisk root application,&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/02/methods-of-rooting-an-android-device/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Methods of rooting an Android Device</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>There isn&#8217;t only one method available to <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#">root</a> all android devices. Instead, every device has different ways to get rooted. However, Several methods are common, from which anyone can help root your device.</p>



<p>Some of the methods to root your device without using a PC are as follows:</p>



<ul>
<li><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ffa500;">Magisk Root</span></li>
</ul>



<p>With the <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Magisk root</a> application, many android devices can get root access. It is an open-source project. As we know that after rooting our device, we don&#8217;t get any OTA update and as the process of rooting your device is not easy, you become frustrated while rooting and unrooting your device. Magisk brings a solution for your frustration, as it is a systemless rooting system, as you can grant root access without touching your device&#8217;s core code.</p>



<ul>
<li><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ffa500;">Framaroot</span></li>
</ul>



<p><a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Framaroot</a> is another application allowing you to root your android device without using a PC. However, it&#8217;s easy to root a device using this application, but a deficient number of devices are supported on their platform. Still, you can try to find with your device&#8217;s name and model number, whether it is supported on their platform or not from <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#">here</a>.</p>



<ul>
<li><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ffa500;">KingRoot</span></li>
</ul>



<p><a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">KingRoot</a> is the application allowing one tap root to its users. It supports several devices to give root access easily on their platform. Indeed, it&#8217;s the first application I used to root my device and learn more about them. However, not every device is supported on their platform but can try that application as it never harms your device.</p>



<ul>
<li><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ffa500;">CF-Auto-Root</span></li>
</ul>



<p><a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CF-Auto-Root</a> is an application created by XDA developers. For beginners who have no or little knowledge about rooting android devices can use this application with closed eyes. However, this application is only used for Samsung and Nexus stock firmware. If you use this application, stay calm as there is no harm because it only installs SuperSU and enables root access.</p>



<ul>
<li><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ffa500;">Virtual Xposed Framework</span></li>
</ul>



<p>Unlike other applications, <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Virtual Xposed</a> never provides full root access in your device, instead, you can install an application that needs root access on their platform and use it. It&#8217;s a free way of gaining root access and consists of a very easy to use framework. The application itself acts as a gateway to root. However, not everything is possible by using this application. But it can give a good experience of a rooted device.</p>



<ul>
<li><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ffa500;">Android x86 Operating System</span></li>
</ul>



<p>Another way of enjoying root access is by installing android x86 OS on your PC. These you can dual boot your PC with such OS and use those for experimental purposes. These Android OS&#8217;s come with pre-installed root access to enable a switch to gain root access. It&#8217;s fun using such operating systems, as you can enjoy a full android framework on PC with total control. Some examples of such OS&#8217;s are <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bliss OS</a>, <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Phoenix OS</a>, <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Remix OS</a>, and several other <a href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/2/blog/post/edit/6434838655018370610/8780580867197378915#" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">x86 OS</a>.</p>



<p>Now it depends on which method you will choose to root your device. However, always stay sure before rooting your device as the method you are using could work or not. Else use virtual Xposed and x86 OS type frameworks to experience root access.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/02/methods-of-rooting-an-android-device/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
