<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Programming &#8211; AhteVirusHub</title>
	<atom:link href="https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/category/programming/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 16:17:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Learn about implementation and algorithm</title>
		<link>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/19/learn-about-implementation-and-algorithm/</link>
					<comments>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/19/learn-about-implementation-and-algorithm/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ahtesham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 16:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Programming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ahtevirus.tech/blog/?p=164</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Learn about algorithm Learn to implement algorithm in the best manner Cons and pros of the algorithms You ever wondered how Google works as what the user demands? Google uses several complex algorithm to provide such impressive results. To understand Algorithms, we can say that it forms the base of any computing program to achieve&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/19/learn-about-implementation-and-algorithm/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Learn about implementation and algorithm</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<ul><li>Learn about algorithm </li><li>Learn to implement algorithm in the best manner </li><li>Cons and pros of the algorithms</li></ul>



<p>You ever wondered how <a href="https://google.co.in/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Google </a>works as what the user demands? Google uses several complex algorithm to provide such impressive results. To understand Algorithms, we can say that it forms the base of any <a href="https://ahtevirus.tech/category/computing/">computing </a>program to achieve the desired result. It is also the first step towards learning the amazing concepts of computer <a href="https://ahtevirus.tech/category/programming/">programming</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">How to implement algorithm in the best way?</h2>



<p>If you know about the basics of computers, you must know that a computer system works by taking an input, then processing it, and providing an output. However, while imputing such algorithms to get an output, you must clearly define each step in an unambiguous and crystal clear manner. While writing algorithms, we always need to try that the process completes the minimum number of steps to solve it. Another thing to consider is finite loops, as it is critical to check that the program should end up in an infinite loop. And the last thing to mention is the algorithm should be designed as language-independent.</p>



<h3 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">Advantages and disadvantages of algorithms</h3>



<p>Algorithms are easy to understand, though it consumes too much time to write algorithms. In algorithms, the problem is broken down into smaller pieces, as it is a stepwise representation of a solution to the given problem. Indeed, it makes it easier to convert into an actual program. However, it is tough to branch and loop statements to show in algorithms.</p>



<h4 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">Algorithms are created in an order</h4>



<p>Algorithms are always written in the order of some parameters. If we discuss how to create algorithms, then we need to know about the sequence:</p>



<ol><li>We need to identify the problem that is needed to be solved.</li><li>We need to find constraints of the problem that are vital to consider while solving.</li><li>We need to create inputs that we need to solve.</li><li>We need to create expected outputs.</li><li>The programmer will need to create a solution to the problem.</li></ol>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/19/learn-about-implementation-and-algorithm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introduction to HTML</title>
		<link>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/09/introduction-to-html/</link>
					<comments>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/09/introduction-to-html/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ahtesham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[HTML]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Programming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ahtevirus.tech/blog/?p=127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[HTML is the acronym of Hyper Text Markup Language. HTML is a standard markup language, using which we can build web sites or several web applications. However, This language is straightforward to learn and understand the programming language. HTML can describe the structure of a webpage, as it consists of a series of elements, and&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/09/introduction-to-html/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Introduction to HTML</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>HTML is the acronym of Hyper Text Markup Language. HTML is a standard markup language, using which we can build web sites or several web applications. However, This language is straightforward to learn and understand the programming language. HTML can describe the structure of a webpage, as it consists of a series of elements, and such features command the browser on how to display any content.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">A simple HTML document with title, heading, and paragraph</h2>



<pre class="wp-block-syntaxhighlighter-code">&lt;!DOCTYPE html>
&lt;html>
&lt;head>
&lt;title>Page Title&lt;/title>
&lt;/head>
&lt;body>

&lt;h1>My First Heading&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>My first paragraph.&lt;/p>

&lt;/body>
&lt;/html></pre>



<p>Here are some basic HTML tags that are always used. However, we will learn about these tags separately. But this code here will provide an output with title, heading, and name. To try it yourself, copy the given code and <a href="https://ahtevirus.tech/html-code-tester/">click here</a>.</p>



<h3 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">HTML Element</h3>



<p>Every HTML element is written under tags. Such tags start with a tag name between greater and smaller than signs (like: &lt;tagname&gt;) and end with a similar title by adding a backslash before the tag name (like: &lt;/tagname&gt;). However, also consider tags as the essential part of an HTML program as if the programmer opens a title and forgets to close such tag, it can pop an error and result in a blank output.</p>



<h4 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">How do browsers use tags?</h4>



<p>Any browser reads the tags and determines how to display content on the web coded in a document file. However, a browser never shows the code itself. It only takes the codes&#8217; help to determine what to display on the page. Still, if something like that happens, then there must be some <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/21066660/page-shows-code-not-rendering" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">errors</a> in the code.</p>



<h5 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">Code Editor</h5>



<p>Nowadays, there are several code editors available. However, we can write the HTML code using any text editors, as what matters is the file extension, which needs to be &#8220;.html&#8221;. Steps to writing such code with Notepad:</p>



<ol><li>Open Notepad.</li><li>Write the above code.</li><li>Click on &#8216;File&#8217; on the menu.</li><li>There choose the &#8216;Save as&#8217; option.</li><li>In the file name area, write &#8220;index.html&#8221;.</li><li>In Save as type, click on the slider menu and choose &#8220;All Files (*.*)&#8221;.</li><li>Set the encoding option below to &#8220;UTF-8&#8221;.</li><li>&#8220;Save&#8221;</li><li>Now to the folder where you have saved the file.</li><li>Right-click on the file.</li><li>Choose &#8220;open with&#8221;.</li><li>And select any browser.</li></ol>



<p>That is it, and now you will be displayed with the content that you have coded. Though this much simple is the language, the central part is your creativity and how you will design your content by coding. However, there are several more things available, which we will cover one by one. And if you also want to learn about such kinds of stuff, then stay connected with the community of <a href="https://ahtevirus.tech/">AhteVirus</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/09/introduction-to-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Learn to code for free and communicate with computer systems</title>
		<link>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/08/learn-to-code-for-free-and-communicate-with-computer-systems-2/</link>
					<comments>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/08/learn-to-code-for-free-and-communicate-with-computer-systems-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ahtesham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 08:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Programming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ahtevirus.tech/blog/?p=123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anyone can learn to code. To learn to code every individual needs passion, 5-10 mins per day, dedication, and a brain to understand the logic. Here you know coding from the ground to up. Learning to code is useful to be a programmer? The language using which we communicate with computer systems is known as&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/08/learn-to-code-for-free-and-communicate-with-computer-systems-2/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Learn to code for free and communicate with computer systems</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Anyone can learn to code. To learn to code every individual needs passion, 5-10 mins per day, dedication, and a brain to understand the logic. Here you know coding from the ground to up.</p>



<h2 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">Learning to code is useful to be a programmer?</h2>



<p>The language using which we communicate with computer systems is known as code. Coding isn’t some alien language, it is just a set of instructions we input using a language that a computer understands. Using codes, we can command a computer, to fulfil several different types of tasks. However, there are several options by which a person can <a href="https://ahtevirus.tech/programming/11/2020/learn-and-create-android-application-without-coding/">learn to program without coding</a>.</p>



<h3 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">What are Programming languages?</h3>



<p>The language which is used to communicate with a computer system is known as the programming language. However, it is observed that at press time, there are around 700 different <a href="https://careerkarma.com/blog/how-many-coding-languages-are-there/#:~:text=According%20to%20Wikipedia%2C%20there%20are,to%20an%20impressive%20245%20languages." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">programming languages</a> available across the world. As humans use different types of languages like English, French, Arabic, Hindi etc. similarly we can use different kinds of languages to communicate with computers.</p>



<h4 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">Why should someone learn to code?</h4>



<p>Learning programming can open up new opportunities and ways for an individual. If an individual learns to code, the person can take the next step to boost their career. However, several individuals learn to code because of curiosity or fun. Indeed, coding can bring our idea into reality. </p>



<h5 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">Fundamentals of programming</h5>



<p>Programming isn’t a challenging subject to cover. The newbie in this career needs to learn about the functions, variables, controlling the flow of code, manipulation of strings and arrays, advanced concepts, all back functions, learning of standard tools to solve real-life problems, using a code editor etc. However, There are numerous career options to choose, like, game development, website building, software development etc. Though a programmer needs to stay updatetd with current affairs about technology.</p>



<h6 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">Some useful programming languages </h6>



<ol><li><span class="has-inline-color has-neve-link-hover-color-color">Python</span></li><li><span class="has-inline-color has-neve-link-hover-color-color">JavaScript</span></li><li><span class="has-inline-color has-neve-link-hover-color-color">Java</span></li><li><span class="has-inline-color has-neve-link-hover-color-color">C#</span></li><li><span class="has-inline-color has-neve-link-hover-color-color">C</span></li><li><span class="has-inline-color has-neve-link-hover-color-color">C++</span></li><li><span class="has-inline-color has-neve-link-hover-color-color">Swift</span></li><li><span class="has-inline-color has-neve-link-hover-color-color">PHP</span></li><li><span class="has-inline-color has-neve-link-hover-color-color">Perl</span></li><li><span class="has-inline-color has-neve-link-hover-color-color">Ruby</span></li><li><span class="has-inline-color has-neve-link-hover-color-color">HTML</span></li><li><span class="has-inline-color has-neve-link-hover-color-color">CSS</span></li></ol>



<p>However, if someone learns these languages, the person can be able to create several advanced levels of software, website, and applications. Indeed, the career as a programmer is terrific, but the most important thing to learn to program is passion. If the person is not interested and wants to learn to program, then the person can never succeed. Anyone can learn to code.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/08/learn-to-code-for-free-and-communicate-with-computer-systems-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Learn and create Android application without coding</title>
		<link>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/01/learn-and-create-android-application-without-coding/</link>
					<comments>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/01/learn-and-create-android-application-without-coding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ahtesham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 08:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android Application]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Programming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ahtevirus.tech/blog/?p=77</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yes, that is possible, if we have ideas and we know the logic, then don’t sit and learn to code, execute our ideas, and bring them to reality. On the web, we can find several different types of platforms that provide us services to create an android application. However, among them most are paid and&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/01/learn-and-create-android-application-without-coding/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Learn and create Android application without coding</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Yes, that is possible, if we have ideas and we know the logic, then don’t sit and learn to code, execute our ideas, and bring them to reality. On the web, we can find several different types of platforms that provide us services to create an android application. However, among them most are paid and expensive, many are based on templates only, and many don’t consist of several features to fulfill our needs.</p>



<h2 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">A free platform to create an android application without coding</h2>



<p>There are several web apps available where we can create android applications like <a href="https://appinventor.mit.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">MIT App inventor</a>, <a href="https://thunkable.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Thunkable</a>, <a href="http://appybuilder.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Appy builder</a>, etc. As these are native platforms they use different lines of codes and have limits in the size of the application. As they use different lines of codes a very small app size also gets boosted, which end ups providing an unoptimized experience.</p>



<h3 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">Best Platform to build android apps without coding</h3>



<p>According to my opinion, <a href="http://sketchware.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Sketchware</a> is the best platform to create android applications using a very easy to understand block language. In skechware’s platform, we can create amazing UI for android applications, just by using a drag and drop feature that makes it very simple to create the line of codes. For UI and main java files what we need is to just drag and drop the blocks according to logic, and the application will itself write the code for us.</p>



<h4 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">Continuing the project to Android Studio</h4>



<p>However, Sketchware uses a different library than Android Studio, we can use the source code file and continue with our project on Android Studio easily. As Sketchware has several features, and components to input, it is not necessary to continue our project to android. When we are getting something that can help to save our time, then what&#8217;s the necessity to make things complicated.</p>



<h5 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">Coders can also use Sketchware</h5>



<p>Sketchware is very convenient to use and can not only help those who don’t know about coding but also can help experienced coders. The features available in it are totally free, however, sometimes they show ads, but not at every point so it is acceptable. We can also purchase an ad-free version that is too cheap if you are creating high-level applications for earning purposes.</p>



<h6 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">Not available for all platform</h6>



<p>The only disadvantage of Sketchware IDE is that it only supports Android operating systems. If you want to use it on devices like PCs or laptops then you will need to install android operating systems on it. However, there are many available android operating systems, like Phoenix OS that can be installed on your device alongside windows and you can enjoy a dual-booting facility.</p>



<h6 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">Where to learn the block language?</h6>



<p>No worries, there are several videos and websites with tutorial blog available on the internet. Not only that soon we will also start with tutorials on our page of <a href="https://ahtevirus.tech/">AhteVirus</a>. In the tutorial, we will start with basics and try to cover as many aspects. Not only programming, but we will try our best to cover everything from designing to external integrations like ads and databases.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We really need support and stay tuned with us.</p>



<p><a href="https://t.me/virusahte/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Join AhteVirus&#8217; Telegram Channel for more information related to technology.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2021/01/01/learn-and-create-android-application-without-coding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Learn to code in HTML language for free</title>
		<link>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/12/learn-code-in-html-language-for-free-with-ahtevirus/</link>
					<comments>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/12/learn-code-in-html-language-for-free-with-ahtevirus/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ahtesham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 13:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A simple HTML Document]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code Editor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How do browsers use tags?]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HTML]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HTML Element]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ahtevirus.tech/?p=316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction to HTML HTML is the acronym of Hyper Text Markup Language. HTML is a standard markup language, using which we can build web sites or several web applications. However, This language is straightforward to learn and understand the programming language. HTML can describe the structure of a webpage, as it consists of a series&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/12/learn-code-in-html-language-for-free-with-ahtevirus/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Learn to code in HTML language for free</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">Introduction to HTML</h2>



<p>HTML is the acronym of Hyper Text Markup Language. HTML is a standard markup language, using which we can build web sites or several web applications. However, This language is straightforward to learn and understand the programming language. HTML can describe the structure of a webpage, as it consists of a series of elements, and such features command the browser on how to display any content.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">A simple HTML document with title, heading, and paragraph</h2>



<pre class="wp-block-syntaxhighlighter-code">&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html&gt;
&lt;head&gt;
&lt;title&gt;Page Title&lt;/title&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;My First Heading&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;</pre>



<p>Here are some basic HTML tags that are always used. However, we will learn about these tags separately. But this code here will provide an output with title, heading, and name. To try it yourself, copy the given code and <a href="https://ahtevirus.tech/html-code-tester/">click here</a>.</p>



<h2 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">HTML Element</h2>



<p>Every HTML element is written under tags. Such tags start with a tag name between greater and smaller than signs (like: &lt;tagname&gt;) and end with a similar title by adding a backslash before the tag name (like: &lt;/tagname&gt;). However, also consider tags as the essential part of an HTML program as if the programmer opens a title and forgets to close such tag, it can pop an error and result in a blank output.</p>



<h2 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">How do browsers use tags?</h2>



<p>Any browser reads the tags and determines how to display content on the web coded in a document file. However, a browser never shows the code itself. It only takes the codes&#8217; help to determine what to display on the page. Still, if something like that happens, then there must be some <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/21066660/page-shows-code-not-rendering">errors</a> in the code.</p>



<h2 class="has-neve-link-color-color has-text-color">Code Editor</h2>



<p>Nowadays, there are several code editors available. However, we can write the HTML code using any text editors, as what matters is the file extension, which needs to be &#8220;.html&#8221;. Steps to writing such code with Notepad:</p>



<ol><li>Open Notepad.</li><li>Write the above code.</li><li>Click on &#8216;File&#8217; on the menu.</li><li>There choose the &#8216;Save as&#8217; option.</li><li>In the file name area, write &#8220;index.html&#8221;.</li><li>In Save as type, click on the slider menu and choose &#8220;All Files (*.*)&#8221;.</li><li>Set the encoding option below to &#8220;UTF-8&#8221;.</li><li>&#8220;Save&#8221;</li><li>Now to the folder where you have saved the file.</li><li>Right-click on the file.</li><li>Choose &#8220;open with&#8221;.</li><li>And select any browser.</li></ol>



<p>That is it, and now you will be displayed with the content that you have coded. Though this much simple is the language, the central part is your creativity and how you will design your content by coding. However, there are several more things available, which we will cover one by one. And if you also want to learn about such kinds of stuff, then stay connected with the community of <a href="https://ahtevirus.tech/">AhteVirus</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ahtevirus.github.io/AhteVirusHub/2020/11/12/learn-code-in-html-language-for-free-with-ahtevirus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
